Russell Carpenter Papers MS041
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Russell Carpenter Papers
1929 -- 1991
1833 -- 2012
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Carpenter, Russell LeGrand
MS041
14.88 Linear Feet 10 oversize boxes, 6 letter size document boxes, 3 legal size document boxes, and 1 half letter size document box
1 Volumes
5 Audiovisual Object(s)
1 Digital Object(s)
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series: Alumni activities at Tufts, 1926-1984; Barnum Museum curatorship and Jumbo talks; Professional papers; Personal papers; Photographs, audio, and visual materials.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the correspondence and collected papers of Russell Carpenter. Over the course of his almost seventy year association with Tufts, Carpenter created and collected photographs, scrapbooks, and memorabilia from his student days (1920-1924); correspondence, photographs, lantern and 35mm slides, and films of the Class of 1924 from their time at Tufts and eleven reunions (1924-1984); documents relating to his alumni activities outside of the Class of 1924; and any and all things related to Jumbo, the elephant, and P. T. Barnum (1938-1975), along with materials related to campus life during the first three-quarters of the 20th century.
Materials related to his position on the Department of Biology's faculty (1938-1969) include course materials, correspondence with members of the Tufts and scientific communities, conference and committee papers, reviews of biology textbooks, and documents that record his interest in ophthalmology, and his lectures on campus and at the Harvard Medical School. A small amount of personal correspondence, records of interests and scrapbook files are also included in the collection.
Related Materials
AC, Artifact Collection, DCA
MS002, Phineas Taylor Barnum, papers, DCA
UA039 Classes, DCA
UA050, Self-study reports, DCA
UP004, Tufts Alumni Review, DCA
Biographical / Historical
Russell LeGrand "Bud" Carpenter (1901-1991), A1924, H1977, was professor of zoology, an active alumnus, and curator of the P.T. Barnum Collection, housed in the Barnum Museum during the more than thirty years he spent at Tufts.
Born in Meriden, Connecticut, in 1901, Carpenter entered Tufts in 1920 intending to study English. He received twenty-five dollars in student aid from the college to help finance his education. After attending the lectures of Professors Herbert Neal and Fred Lambert in biology, Carpenter changed his major to biology. During his undergraduate years, he wrote a column for the Tufts Weekly, sang in the Glee Club, and also played the banjo in a small dance orchestra. He was also a member and, later, an adviser, of the Kappa chapter of the Zeta Psi fraternity on campus.
Following graduation from Tufts in 1924, he entered graduate school at Harvard University, and received a doctorate in zoology in 1928. That same year, he married Elsie Stuart Clark, with whom he later had two children, Russell and Cynthia, and he then started teaching at the College of Physicians and Surgeons at Columbia University.
Carpenter returned to Tufts in 1938 as professor of zoology, undertaking both teaching and research activities that led to the establishment of the Radiobiology Research Laboratory, of which he served as director and principal investigator. He focused his research on the biological effects of microwave radiation, particularly on the eye, and published more than a dozen papers on the subject. Soon after his return to Medford, he and his family took up residence at 126 Packard Avenue, where they lived for the next eighteen years.
Carpenter was also a lecturer in ophthalmology at Harvard Medical School for more than twenty-five years and acted as a consultant on ophthalmic history for the Retina Foundation in Boston. He received many scientific honors, including election as a Fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences.
Beyond his teaching duties, Carpenter's involvement with Tufts as an alumnus was substantial. For almost seventy years, he served as secretary of the Class of 1924, organizing reunions and coordinating the exchange of information among class members. He was the first editor of the Tufts Alumni Review, the president of the New York Tufts Club, and, beginning in 1943, a member of the Tufts Alumni Council. He received the Tufts Alumni Distinguished Service Award in 1942 and also served on the committees in charge of redesigning the Tufts Seal and the Tufts Chair.
Carpenter undertook the responsibility of establishing the Tufts Barnum Collection, which included letters and personal mementos of P.T. Barnum. Acting as the collection's curator, Carpenter spread the story of Tufts and Jumbo through his notable, witty lectures and slide shows.
In March 1968, for the first time in his thirty years as a professor, Carpenter presented a lecture on the history of Jumbo and how he "happened to matriculate" to his Biology 2 classes at Tufts. President Hallowell was extended an invitation to attend the morning course. Carpenter's personal photographs of almost all of the objects in the collection became invaluable to the institution following a 1975 fire which destroyed Barnum Museum and all of its contents.
Carpenter retired from Tufts in 1969. The following year he was invited to establish and direct a program of microwave bio-effects research for the Bureau of Radiological Health of the U.S. Food and Drug Administration. In 1977, Tufts presented Carpenter with an honorary degree, recognizing his life-long dedication to his alma mater, both professionally and personally.
Carpenter died in Williamstown, Massachusetts, on July 28, 1991.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Carpenter, Russell L.; Carmichael, Leonard; Neal, Herbert C.; Barnum, P.T. (Phineas Taylor); Lewis, Leo R.; Dept. of Biology; Class of 1924; Alumni Council; Alumni Association; Zeta Psi; Lambert-Kingsley Society; Museums; Mascots; 126 Packard Avenue --Medford Campus --Medford (Mass.); Barnum Hall; Barnum Museum of Natural History; University history
- Alumni activities at Tufts, 1926 -- 1985; 1934 -- 1979; MS041.001; 1.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains Russell L. Carpenter's correspondence, personal notes, ledgers, and accounts of Class of 1924's eleven organized reunions (1934-84). The earlier reunion folders contain the bulk of the materials, although the 50th reunion folders include numerous letters from class members who could not attend. Questionnaires filled out by class members, contact lists, schedules of activities and Carpenter's notes detail this distinct group of people through World War II, the Baby Boom, and into retirement.
  Also included in this series are documents related to Carpenter's service on Tufts Alumni Council and his membership in the Tufts Alumni Association, and committees that studied Tufts night at the Boston Pops, the Tufts chair, and fund-raising efforts. There is a small amount of correspondence pertaining to his service as president of the Tufts Club of New York (1936-37).
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged by subject, then alphabetically, then chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Class of 1924 - 10th reunion, 1934; MS041.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1924 - 20th reunion, 1944; MS041.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1924 - 25th reunion, 1949; MS041.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1924 - 25th reunion, 1949; MS041.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1924 - 45th reunion - boasts and confessions, 1969; MS041.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1924 - 50th reunion, 1974; MS041.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1924 - 50th reunion, 1974; MS041.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1924 - 50th reunion - letters, 1974; MS041.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Class of 1924 - 50th reunion (3 Name tag /Buttons), 1974; MS041.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
    Two of the buttons are labeled; one with "Bud Carpenter" and the other with "Elsie Carpenter" and the third is blank.
  - Class of 1924 - 55th reunion, 1979; MS041.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - A dandruff football game, [music], 1926; MS041.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Association by-laws, 1952 -- 1953; MS041.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Alumni Council - nominating committee, 1944; MS041.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Tufts alumni fund, 1936 -- 1938; MS041.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Tufts chair [furniture], 1965; MS041.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1924 - addresses, 1934; MS041.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - 15th reunion -[class of 1924], 1939; MS041.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1924 - 30th reunion, 1954; MS041.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
    Includes Tufts Alumni Day name tag.
  - Class of 1924 - 35th reunion, 1959; MS041.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1924 - 40th reunion, 1964; MS041.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1924 - 40th reunion (Response card), 1964; MS041.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1924 - 45th reunion, 1964; MS041.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - Class of 1924 - 50th reunion (1924 Kitty for 50th reunion), 1974; MS041.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - [Tufts Alumni Council], 1940 -- 1957; MS041.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - [Alumni correspondence], 1941 -- 1975; MS041.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Council, 1944 -- 1985; MS041.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Council committee on [Boston] Pops - Tufts night, 1946; MS041.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Alumni Council nominations, 1944 -- 1946; MS041.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Joe Morton [Bureau of Alumni Relations correpsondence], 1934; MS041.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Tufts Alumni Council second century fund report #1, 1949 -- 1950; MS041.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Tufts Club [Tufts College Alumni Association of New York], 1936 -- 1937; MS041.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
- Barnum Museum curatorship and Jumbo talks, 1873 -- 1985; 1938 -- 1985; MS041.002; 1.0 Linear Feet
  This series contains materials related to Russell L. Carpenter's curatorship of the Barnum Museum. The majority of the documents are correspondence from children and adults, seeking information about and photographs of Jumbo. Also included in this series are lists of the slides used in Carpenter's Jumbo and Barnum talks, requests for him to present his talks at local events, accounts of the creation of the Barnum study room, Jumbo trivia, and correspondence with the Louis Paul Jonas family, who were the taxidermists responsible for Jumbo's periodic restorations. There are also accounts of the 1975 fire, inventory and losses lists, and information related to the disposal of the other animals in the museum's collection.
  This series is arranged alphabetically, then chronologically.
  - [The Barnum and Bailey songster], MS041.002.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Alexander [Correspondence], 1961 -- 1973; MS041.002.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - [Correspondence], 1873 -- 1984; MS041.002.004.00003 (Box 4)
    Contains a letter and picture about the Fiji Mermaid.
    Hoaxes; Fiji; Mermaids
  - [Correspondence], 1939 -- 1961; MS041.002.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - [Correspondence], 1954 -- 1976; MS041.002.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - [Correspondence], 1971 -- 1976; MS041.002.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - History of Animals and Leading Curiosities, 1878; MS041.002.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Inventory - Barnum room, 1975; MS041.002.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Louis Paul Jonas [Jumbo restoration], 1930 -- 1975; MS041.002.004.00009 (Box 4)
    Contains "The Mounting of an Elephant Group" written by Louis Jonas which is about taxidermy.
  - [Jumbo and Barnum talk notecards], 1985; MS041.002.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo - from the scrapbooks in the library of the Royal Zoological Society's Gardens - the London Zoo in Regents' Park, MS041.002.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo March (Dygert), 1882; MS041.002.004.00012 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo's measurements, 1941; MS041.002.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - Jumbo's skeleton - N.Y. Museum of Natural History, MS041.002.004.00014 (Box 4)
  - Letters after loss of Jumbo, 1975; MS041.002.004.00015 (Box 4)
  - Origins of Jumbo's name, MS041.002.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - "That Mascot" [sheet music], MS041.002.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Jumbo-Related, 1968 -- 1975; MS041.002.004.00018 (Box 4)
  - ["Who was P.T. Barnum?" by Russell L. Carpenter Invitation Card], MS041.002.004.00019 (Box 4)
    Cards; Lectures or lecturing
  - [Correspondence on Grant Account No. BFIAIU], 1974 -- 1975; MS041.002.004.00020 (Box 4)
  - Barnum collection - curator, MS041.002.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Barnum museum, MS041.002.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - [Barnum's show], MS041.002.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - [Barnum's show and circus], MS041.002.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - [Correspondence], MS041.002.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Requests for information on Jumbo, MS041.002.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - P.T. Barnum Family, MS041.002.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - P.T. Barnum [Articles & Memorabilia], 1875 -- 1960; MS041.002.005.00008 (Box 5)
    Contains an admissions ticket "To Family Circle of P.T. Barnum's Great Roman Hippodrome" from July 2, 1875.
    Tickets
  - Jumbo Articles, 1915 -- 1976; MS041.002.005.00009 (Box 5)
    Includes articles written by Russell L. Carpenter, "Jumbo, We Revere Thee-?" and "P.T. Barnum's Jumbo."
  - Barnum Fire [Articles], 1975 -- 1977; MS041.002.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - [Barnum Memorabilia Articles], 1980; MS041.002.005.00011 (Box 5)
- Professional papers, 1874 -- 1987; 1938 -- 1969; MS041.003; 1.5 Linear Feet; 1 Volumes
  Much of this series contains correspondence between Russell L. Carpenter and numerous colleagues, students, publishing companies, and salesmen. There is a small amount of information of the Lambert-Kingsley Society, a student organization in the Dept. of Biology, and materials related to Carpenter's conference trip to Japan. Also of note is series of pen and ink drawings, "Shades of Barnum," that comically illustrate Biology students' activities around 1948. An anthology of Carpenter's published papers, compiled in 2001, is also included in the series.
  This series is arranged by subject, then alphabetically.
  - Biology 1 - Botany [correspondence], MS041.003.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence], MS041.003.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence], MS041.003.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence], MS041.003.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence], 1930 -- 1960; MS041.003.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence], 1939 -- 1971; MS041.003.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence], 1941 -- 1958; MS041.003.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence and lecture notes], MS041.003.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence], MS041.003.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence], MS041.003.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Correspondence, Professional, 1940 -- 1987; MS041.003.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - [Correspondence from W. E. Castle to Professor Lane], 1916 -- 1920; MS041.003.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - [Elsie S. Clark Correspondence to H. W. Wilson Company], 1928; MS041.003.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - AF41(657)86 - Appointments [Research in microwave biology staff], MS041.003.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Amphibean materials [conference correspondence], MS041.003.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Anatomy 221 [the sense organs], MS041.003.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Association for research in opthamology, MS041.003.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Carnegie self-study [Tufts], MS041.003.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Civil service papers - R. L. Carpenter, MS041.003.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Exp. [Experimental] college nat. [natural] sciences course, MS041.003.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - Lambert-Kingsley society, MS041.003.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - L-K [Lambert-Kingsley] faculty show, MS041.003.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - Histology, MS041.003.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - History of biology [Biology 196], 1961 -- 1965; MS041.003.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - [Resolution on the retirement of professor Russell L. Carpenter], MS041.003.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - R. L. Carpenter Bibliography, MS041.003.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - International Federation for Medical & Biological Engineering and International Conference on Medical Electronics and Biological Engineering, 1965 -- 1967; MS041.003.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - Who's who [correspondence], MS041.003.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - Bronze tablet for Ballou Hall - Bob Nichols, John holmes, R. L. C. [Russell L. Carpenter], MS041.003.007.00016 (Box 7)
  - Carmichael [Leonard C.] dinner, 1952; MS041.003.007.00017 (Box 7)
  - Leo Lewis [an appreciation], MS041.003.007.00018 (Box 7)
  - Bob McCarthy [student], MS041.003.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - Herbert V. Neal [memorial and lecture hall dedication], MS041.003.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - Tufts Anti-Fraternity and Sorority Campaign, 1952 -- 1963; MS041.003.007.00021 (Box 7)
  - [National Elephant Collectors Society Correspondence], 1985; MS041.003.007.00022 (Box 7)
  - NSF Proposal, MS041.003.007.00023 (Box 7)
    Proposal from the Biology Department to the National Science Foundation.
  - [Song Book of the Tufts College Biology Club], 1928; MS041.003.007.00024 (Box 7)
  - [Twenty-Fifth Annual Biological Conference of Eastern New England Colleges, April 22, 1967], MS041.003.007.00025 (Box 7)
  - [Tufts War Fund Drive Newspaper Articles], 1940 -- 1942; MS041.003.007.00026 (Box 7)
  - [Office of Research Coordinator Research Summary for the Month of May 1965: Awards and Renewals], MS041.003.007.00027 (Box 7)
  - [Tufts News Notes], 1969; MS041.003.007.00028 (Box 7)
  - [Model of the Canal of Cloquet or Hyaloid Canal with Description], 1926; MS041.003.007.00029 (Box 7)
    The model was found with a short description of the Canal of Cloquet also called the Hyaloid Canal, but it is unknown if the diagram is actually the Canal of Cloquet.
  - Three Trade Cards for the Maud S. Halter Issued by J.C. Lighthouse, Rochester, N.Y., 1882; MS041.003.007.00030 (Box 7)
    Trade; Cards
  - [The Model Ophthalmologist Song Composed for Course 488], 1950; MS041.003.007.00031 (Box 7)
  - [Lewis Frederick Manly Biography], MS041.003.007.00032 (Box 7)
  - [Handwritten Sign with Business Hours], MS041.003.007.00033 (Box 7)
    This sign may have been used for the Barnum Museum or Russell L. Carpenter's office hours for students.
  - ["For Jumbo" Pin], MS041.003.007.00034 (Box 7)
    White and Blue pin featuring Jumbo bearing a "T" and "For Jumbo" written around the edge.
  - Correspondence, 1938 -- 1962; MS041.003.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Shades of Barnum, 1948; MS041.003.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - [P.T. Barnum's Desk Manufacturing Information], MS041.003.008.00003 (Box 8)
    A handwritten sheet of paper; date unknown.
  - Brass/Iron Handle from P.T. Barnum's desk, 1874; MS041.003.008.00004 (Box 8)
    The handle is possibly made of either iron or brass.
    Handles; Desks; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor)
  - [Brass/Iron Manufacturer's Plaque from P.T. Barnum's Desk], 1874; MS041.003.008.00005 (Box 8)
    The plaque is possibly made of brass or iron. It is inscribed with "Manufactured by the Wooton Desk CO. Indianapolis, IND. PAT. OCT. 6. 1874."
    Desks; Plaques; Barnum, P. T. (Phineas Taylor)
  - Microwave-induced cataracts: collected research papers by Russell L. Carpenter, MS041.003.009.00001 (Box Volume 9)
- Personal papers, 1908 -- 1990; 1938 -- 1969; MS041.004; 0.5 Linear Feet
  This series contains biographic information for Russell L. Carpenter, personal correspondence, a number of folders of unfinished scrapbook materials that cover events both personal and professional, and a small amount of information pertaining to Zeta Psi fraternity at Tufts.
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  75 years from the date of creation. Open for research.
  - Biography - Vitae - R. L. C., MS041.004.010.00001 (Box 10)
    75 years from the date of creation.
  - [Correspondence], MS041.004.010.00002 (Box 10)
  - [Correspondence], 1938; MS041.004.010.00003 (Box 10)
  - Danvers, James [E1924, obituary, brother-in-law], MS041.004.010.00004 (Box 10)
  - M. B. L. [Marine Biology Laboratory] Tennis Club, MS041.004.010.00005 (Box 10)
  - Honorary degree from Tufts, 1977; MS041.004.010.00006 (Box 10)
  - Laboratory School [Tufts Nursery School], MS041.004.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, MS041.004.010.00008 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook, MS041.004.010.00009 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook - personal, MS041.004.010.00010 (Box 10)
  - Scrapbook - personal, MS041.004.010.00011 (Box 10)
  - [Tufts memorabilia ], 1920 -- 1921; MS041.004.010.00012 (Box 10)
  - Zeta Psi, MS041.004.010.00013 (Box 10)
  - [Zeta Psi, correspondence], MS041.004.010.00014 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1939 -- 1990; MS041.004.010.00015 (Box 10)
  - Newspaper Clippings and Press Releases, 1938 -- 1981; MS041.004.010.00016 (Box 10)
  - Scholarship: Correspondence, 1921 -- 1925; MS041.004.010.00017 (Box 10)
  - Veterans Administration: Account Book and Letter, 1944 -- 1945; MS041.004.010.00018 (Box 10)
  - Deed Transfers of Personal Property, 1927 -- 1941; MS041.004.010.00019 (Box 10)
  - Papers Relating to Property at 37 Warren St., 1908 -- 1927; MS041.004.010.00020 (Box 10)
  - Hullaballou - Faculty Show, 1903 -- 1957; MS041.004.010.00021 (Box 10)
    Includes photographs of the faculty in costume
    Photographs
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1966 -- 1967; MS041.004.010.00022 (Box 10)
  - [The Travelers Insurance Company Correspondence], 1940; MS041.004.010.00023 (Box 10)
  - [Armistice Day Football Coburn vs. Tufts Second, Seaverns Field], 1921; MS041.004.010.00024 (Box 10)
  - [Tufts College Tuition Bill for John P. Moser], 1920; MS041.004.010.00025 (Box 10)
  - [Certificate for the Senior Dramatic Society Pen, Paint, and Pretzels], 1924; MS041.004.010.00026 (Box 10)
- Photographs, audio and visual material, 1833 -- 2012; 1934 -- 1979; MS041.005; 4.05 Linear Feet; 5 Audiovisual Object(s); 1 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains the multimedia components of the collection. The majority of the contents of this series were created and collected by Carpenter, as the reunion organizer for the Class of 1924. The audio cassette tapes are recordings of Carpenter's "talks" that accompanied the 35 mm slides of P.T. Barnum and Jumbo, which were sent to alumni groups around the country. The lantern slides of Jumbo and Tufts illustrated Carpenter's talks on Tufts history. The films also capture both activities of the Class of 1924, such as "jams," and historic buildings on campus, including Barnum Museum.
  This series is arranged by medium, then alphabetically.
  - Jumbo Ashes in Peanut Butter Jar, 2012; MS041.005.00001
  - Scrapbook of the Class of 1924, 1924 -- 1979; MS041.005.011.001 (Box 11)
  - 35 mm slides, MS041.005.012
    - [Class of 1924 - 10th, 25th, 35th reunions, Tufts campus, ice storm, new dorm construction, Cindy's letter], MS041.005.012.00001 (Box 12)
    - [Class of 1924 - 40th, 45th, 50th, 60th reunions, reunion titles], MS041.005.012.00002 (Box 12)
    - Barnum unused and extra slides, Jumbo, MS041.005.012.00003 (Box 12)
    - [Jumbo talk, Jumbo - London, Barnum talk, ROTC war college, engineering night rejects], MS041.005.012.00004 (Box 12)
  - Bud [Russell L. ] Carpenter '24 Zeta Psi Tufts [scrapbook], 1920 -- 1924; MS041.005.013.001 (Box 13)
  - Photographs and negatives, 1882 -- 1957; MS041.005.014
    - 1929 Alumni Day - Tufts [negatives], MS041.005.014.00001 (Box 14)
    - Alumni Day, Dr. and Mrs. Lee at Fair, April 1939, 2 of the barn [negatives], MS041.005.014.00002 (Box 14)
    - [Class of 1924], MS041.005.014.00003 (Box 14)
    - Class of 1924 - Photographs and scrapbook, MS041.005.014.00004 (Box 14)
    - Hullaballou [faculty show], 1957; MS041.005.014.00005 (Box 14)
    - Jumbo [negatives], MS041.005.014.00006 (Box 14)
    - [Kappa - Theta Delta Chi], 100th anniversary [negatives], 1956; MS041.005.014.00007 (Box 14)
    - [Lambert-Kingsley Society], 1942; MS041.005.014.00008 (Box 14)
    - [Memorial] Gate and Theta-Delta-Chi House, July 1930 [Negatives], MS041.005.014.00009 (Box 14)
    - Old Pictures [Negatives, Tufts], MS041.005.014.00010 (Box 14)